SUMMARY

Experienced Full-stack Software Engineer with 7 years, specializes in back-end development and system design. Worked on management systems, e-commerce, telecom, and real estate apps, etc. Key roles include requirement analysis, architecture design, feature development, and mentoring junior developers.

SKILLS



OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS

- * Published Python Package: pypi.org/search/?q=piash
- * Leetcode: leetcode.com/piash001
- * uhunt: uhunt.onlinejudge.org/id/163294
- * Stack Overflow:
- stackoverflow.com/users/5958526/piash
- * National Collegiate Programming Contest (2013)
- * Intra programming contest, 2nd position (2015)

EXPERIENCE

AD Group - Senior Software Engineer

10/2022 - Present

- * Lead junior team members .
- * Integrating Infobip, SQS, Slack, Zapier, etc., developing and managing cache strategies, OTP, microservices security, and Docker.
- * Project: Real-estate service portal for VMG Australia

Portonics LTD. - Software Engineer

12/2021 - 09/2022

- * Implemented S3 bucket, cache & worker, date translator for locales, automated maintenance mode
- * Designed CMS architecture, package & reward system, profile manager, etc. for telecom app
- * Project: Dtac, telecom app for Telenor Thailand

Leaping Logic LLC - Web Developer

10/2020 - 11/2021

- * Implemented payment systems like **Stripe**, checkout process, delivery tracking, discount, price management, etc. for retail solutions.
- * Developed various CMS features for product owners in a multi-vendor system.
- * Project: RentMy, Texas-based retail solution for both rent and sell

LinkVision Software Solution - Software Engineer 08/2019 - 09/2020

- * Lead junior team members for both back and front-end.
- * Designed and developed functionalities for a Human Resource Management solution, including, leave, payroll, claims, benefits, RBAC, recruitment etc.
- * Project: Human Resource Management System for Robi Axiata

DataQuest Tech LTD. - Web Developer

04/2018 - 07/2019

- * Designed and developed a diagnostic & healthcare platform as a full-stack dev.
- * Built tools for chart and automated article generation.
- * Project: Thyrocare (diagnostic & healthcare platform), Zsenia (share-market investment & analytics platform)

Control N Digital - Junior Web Developer

05/2017 - 03/2018

* Designed and developed various e-commerce site, POS and their functionalities as a full-stack dev.

EDUCATION

Masters in Information and Technology

University of Dhaka (2018 - 2019)

B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology (2012-2016)